

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

(+1) 407-601.9438 victorteppa@gmail.com Kissimmee, FL. 34744

https://vteppaweb.github.io/resume/index.html

Professional Summary

I am an Information Technology professional with overseas creativity and passionate experience with a high level of academic education based on my bachelor degree in computer science.

Determination to learn new technologies, proactive attitude, written and verbal communication are just some of my key strengths, which will make me a very competitive candidate.

Others key strengths that I possess include, but are not limited to, the following:

- My knowledge on life cycle development software.
- I am a self-starter, bilingual and an excellent team worker.
- Responsive web application design.
- My passion and ability to create apps and website solutions.
- Front End Web Design and Development.
- Always willing to learn and stay tune with the latest technologies.
- Knowledge of SEO, KPI's, SSRS.

It would be great to have the opportunity that allow me to have a professional development and continue my career as front end web developer.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Experience

Website Front End Design & Development

Victor Teppa Online Resume / Portfolio Orlando, United States. Aug, 2020 – Dec, 2020.

- Design website look & feel.
- Create responsive and mobile first web design using Bootstrap4 framework.
- Analysis, Design and Implementation of SEO best practices, Google Search Visibility,
 On-Page Ranking Optimization Factors.
- GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP4, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Chrome Developer Tool, Sublime Text Editor.

Front End Web Developer

GeoSnapShot Sydney, Australia. Sep, 2015 – Sep, 2017.

- Maintenance of the web pages look & feel.
- Evaluation of new changes under new web templates.
- Create responsive HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript web templates.
- Work on changes using (GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Sublime Text Editor).

Web Application Developer

MS21Consulting. Venezuela. April 2012 – Jan, 2013.

- Analyse, design, development and maintenance of the desktop, web applications, web services and windows services implemented.
- Responsible for the development of Front End and Back End of the projects.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, C#. NET, JavaScript, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server.
- **Architectures**: SOA, MVC and 3-Tier.

> Victor Rafael Teppa Delfino

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Analysts & Web Developer App

NewTech Sistemas, C.A. Venezuela. Nov, 2009 – March, 2012.

Design and development of web applications to supervise and monitoring the products samples of the sales department of multinational 3M Manufacture Company.
 Software Used: IBM I-Series AS/400, MS-IE 7-8, Firefox 4.0, MS-Office, IBM Lotus Notes 8.5, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2003/2010, MS-Project, Reporting Services 2007, OlinkView 9.0, Cisco IP Communicator.

Front End Web Application Developer

Grupo SMS, C.A. Venezuela. July, 2007 – Oct, 2009.

- Design and Development of new web applications. The most important projects developed using this programs were:
 - 1. Creation of a Microsoft SharePoint web application to supervise and monitoring the workflow of the process of all departments of the multinational company: Movistar Telefonica Venezuela. Project duration: 10 months.
 - 2. Collaboration in the design and development of the Look & Feel of web applications.
- **Software Used:** IE 6-7, Firefox, MS-Office, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2005, MS-Project, MS-Reporting Services 2005, MS-SQL Server 2005, MS-SharePoint Server and SharePoint Designer 2007.
- **Architectures:** 3-Tier, MVC and SOA.

Multimedia eLearning Developer

The eLearning Solutions, C.A. Venezuela. Sep, 2005 – May, 2007.

- Collaborate with the creative illustrator and design department.
- Develop the learning platform with the supplied files and tools using Macromedia
 Flash and coding all characters movements.
- Work in the design and development of the Look & Feel in all projects.

Venezuelan – Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Education:

Nueva Esparta University.

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. Caracas – Venezuela, 2006.

Courses & Seminaries:

CodeWithMosh.com

Modern JavaScript/ES6.

Learn ECMAScript 6 JavaScript features for web and mobile app developers. 2021

Coursera.org by UCDAVIS University of California.

SEO - Search Engine Optimization.

SEO Optimization / Fundamentals / Best Practices / Advanced Content and Social Tactics to Optimize SEO / Optimizing a Website for Search. 2020.

Coursera.org by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

Front End Web UI Frameworks and Tools. Bootstrap, Angular, Node.js, NPM, Lite-Server, JSON, Git, CSS Pre-processors Less and Sass. 2020.

Coursera Project Network.

Position Elements on a Page with CSS. HTML5, CSS3. 2020.

Coursera.org by University of Michigan.

Front End Web Design, Development and Coding. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap4 and Advanced Responsive Design. 2020.

TAFE Ultimo, New South Wales.

Web Design & Development (Certificate III and IV). Sydney, Australia. 2014 – 2015

Navitas English Institute.

Academic English level 2 and 3. Sydney, Australia. 2014

> Victor Rafael Teppa Delfino

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Navitas English Institute.

IELTS Preparation Course. Sydney, Australia. 2013

Navitas English Institute.

General English Course. Brisbane, Australia. 2013

Navitas English Institute.

FCE – Cambridge First Certificate English. Brisbane, Australia. 2013

Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Adobe After Effects 7.0 Pro

This course was instructed by an approved member of the Adobe Authorized Training Provider in Venezuela. 2006.

Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Macromedia Fireworks MX 2004
This course was instructed by a fully-accredited member of the Macromedia Authorized Training Partner in Venezuela.
2004.

Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

Adobe Flash MX 2004 Advanced Development (Action Script). This course was instructed by a fully-accredited member of the Macromedia Authorized Training Partner in Venezuela. 2003.

CASE Institute.

Web Design. Caracas - Venezuela 2001.

Instituto de Capacitación Técnica KEYS.

Networks Seminary. Caracas - Venezuela 2000.

Luisa Cáceres de Arismendi Institute.

Technical repair and maintenance of personal computers. Caracas - Venezuela 1997.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

Hard Skills:

- Life Cycle of Web Applications.
- Advanced Responsive Web Design.
- SEO, KPI's, Reporting Services and Google Analytics.
- Front End Web UI / UX Libraries.
- HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript ES6, Typescript, Bootstrap, Node.js, Npm, MongoDB.
- Version control systems Git / Bit-Bucket.
- SQL-Server Databases.
- Basic knowledge of ASP.NET, MVC, C#, Razor, LINQ, Entity Framework.
- CMS: DNN / Site core / Microsoft SharePoint Designer.
- LMS Learning Management Systems Experience (eLearning).
- Adobe & Macromedia: Dreamweaver / Fireworks / Photoshop / After Effects / Flash.
- Image, Video and Audio Edition.

Soft Skills:

- Bilingual: English / Spanish.
- Multicultural, Collaboration, Communication Mindset.
- Detail Oriented and Proactive.
- CPR and First Aid Certification.
- Fitness and Personal Trainer Certifications.
- Culinary Skills.